

Mattia Scalas

Born and raised in Sardinia (Italy), after an academic career in architecture and planning I specialized in GIS with an interest in computer science applied to data analysis in urban and climatic contexts. Pythonist, sports lover, I never stop learning

Work Experience

Urban climate data analyst **CMCC** Foundation (Remote) March 2023

Microclimate simulations, data analysis, technical writing, research activity

Adjunct professor Politecnico di Torino (Turin) September 2022 - December 2023

Subjects: Geographic Information Systems (GIS), urban planning

Researcher R3C Centre (Turin)

November 2020 - December 2023

Multi-risk urban assessment framework development

Collaborator OnStairs s.r.l. (Remote)

April 2020 - December 2023

IT and cybersecurity free online courses

Athlete

Atletica Casone Noceto (Parma) January 2014 - December 2017

National U23 champion 10k road race 2015 2x national U23 team convocation

Education

PhD Candidate Expected graduation: April 2024

DIST - Politecnico di Torino

November 2020 - December 2023

Thesis: Framing the local resilience unit as a post-pandemic planning paradigm

Master: Talents for Fundraising CRT Foundation

March 2020 - December 2020

Master's degree: territorial and urban planning

Politecnico di Torino

October 2017 - December 2019

Bachelor's degree: architecture Politecnico di Torino

October 2017 - December 2019

IT skills

QGIS, ArcGIS Pro, Carto, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, NETCDF, Microsoft Office, PostgreSQL

Languages

English (Advanced), Portuguese (Beginner)

Passions

(Geo)Data Science

Machine Learning

Reading

Track and Field

➤ Travel